# Marcela Pantoja

## **SUMMARY**

I am a Senior currently attending the University of Texas at Dallas with a graduation date of December 2023. I spent my first two years of university at UTRGV where I learned the fundamentals of Computer Science as well as some higher-level skills before transferring to UTD. I am knowledgeable in many programming languages, with a proficiency in C++, Java, and Python. Through my internships, I have gained experience in software product engineering, internal software application management, managing a team, and more.

## **EDUCATION**

# Bachelor's Degree | 2023 | University of Texas at Dallas

August 2021 - December 2023

Major: Computer Science

## **SKILLS**

#### o Personal Skills

Problem Solving	Critical Thinking	Communication	Adaptability
Teamwork	Organization	Leadership	Creativity
Project Management	Analytics	Scheduling	

Technological Skills

JavaC++PythonSpringMicrosoft OfficeGitMavenJenkinsAgileJiraRScikit-learn

Keras TensorFlow

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

## **SWE (Digital Enterprise Solutions) Intern** – CISCO, Remote TX

May 2022 - August 2022

For the duration of the internship, I worked in a team under the Legal IT department on a project that put me in close contact with both the IT and the Business side of legal. My main project was to create a WebEx chatbot that would redirect traffic flow from the 'Ask Legal' chat space and allow Legal Business to spend less manpower maintaining the chat. Our project also included creating a POC document showing legal business how to maintain the bot in the future.

My team and I were also asked to help in the development of an expedited notification bot that would deliver reminders to every employee across the company who had not completed their mandatory trainings.

# SWE (Infrastructure Solutions Group) Intern – Dell Technologies, Remote TX

May 24, 2021 - August 13, 2021

For the duration of the internship, I worked on multiple projects that required me to work closely with DELL's InsidelQ and CloudlQ teams. The beginning projects revolved around adding new features

to the PowerStore product and engineering informational reports for the Product Management Unit. The main project had another intern and I collaborate on a sensitive information anonymizer for the PowerStore product.

This internship led to me becoming more knowledgeable about how a product goes from a concept, to testing, to finally being put into production. Some of the aspects I learned about are; pushing and merging code, testing code in a dev space, thoroughly debugging code and checking for thread safety, and how to document information for POC pages and reports.

# **Student Academic Assistant** – *UTRGV*, *Edinburg TX*

October 2020 - May 2021

My role was to oversee my university's Express Advising Zoom meetings, this consisted of me managing all the peer advisors and incoming students. I was also tasked with recording confidential information regarding the students and reporting that information daily to my supervisor.